Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and today we have a very serious dialogue for you.
我是Katherine，今天我们为大家准备了一段非常严肃的对话。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to talk about a will and testament, the last will and testament of someone.
我们要讨论一份遗嘱和遗言，某人的最后遗嘱和遗言。
Alright, so what is a will and testament?
好的，那么什么是遗嘱和遗言呢？
Well basically this is a document that someone writes, usually with a lawyer, that explains
嗯，基本上这是一份由某人（通常与律师一起）撰写的文件，它说明了
what to do with the person's body and their possessions, their things, after they die.
这个人去世后，如何处理其遗体以及财产、物品。
So many people write these and the family will then use it to discover who gets to receive
所以很多人会写这种文件，然后家人会用它来了解谁将获得
certain objects and what to do with this person's body.
某些物品，以及如何处理这个人的遗体。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So that is a last will and testament.
这就是最后遗嘱和遗言。
We are going to take a look at an example of one so you would see more or less in English
我们将看一个例子，这样你就能大致了解用英语
how one is written.
如何撰写一份遗嘱。
Now obviously they can be very long and very complex.
显然，它们可能非常长且非常复杂。
So we've taken one that has some interesting words there that are a little bit more specific,
所以我们选了一个包含一些有趣词汇的版本，这些词汇比较具体，
a lot of legal terms there.
有很多法律术语。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time and we'll be back shortly.
那么，我们先听一遍这段对话，稍后再回来。
Last will and testament of Luke Thompson.
卢克·汤普森的最后遗嘱和遗言。
I Luke Thompson residing in California, being of sound mind, do hereby declare this instrument
我，卢克·汤普森，居住在加利福尼亚州，心智健全，特此声明本文件
to be my last will and testament.
为我的最后遗嘱和遗言。
I hereby revoke all previous wills and codicils.
我特此撤销所有先前的遗嘱和遗嘱附录。
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
我指示我的遗体处理方式如下。
I'm to be cremated and taken to the summit of Mount Everest where my ashes will forever
我将被火化，并带到珠穆朗玛峰之巅，我的骨灰将永远
remain at the ceiling of the earth.
留在地球的最高点。
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to my spouse, Betty Thompson, should she survive
我将我遗产的所有剩余部分给予我的配偶贝蒂·汤普森，前提是她
me for 60 days.
在我去世后存活60天。
If my spouse, Betty Thompson, does not survive me, I give all the rest and residue of my
如果我的配偶贝蒂·汤普森未能比我存活更久，我将我遗产的所有剩余部分
estate to English Pod.
给予EnglishPod。
If neither Betty Thompson nor English Pod survives me, I give all the rest and residue
如果贝蒂·汤普森和EnglishPod都未能比我存活更久，我将我遗产的所有剩余部分
of my estate to my heirs as determined by the laws of the state of California relating
给予根据加利福尼亚州关于继承和分配的法律所确定的
to descent and distribution.
我的继承人。
I appoint Robert Porter to act as the executor of this will, to serve without bond.
我任命罗伯特·波特担任本遗嘱的执行人，无需提供担保。
Should Robert Porter be unable or unwilling to serve, then I appoint Jason Smalls to act
如果罗伯特·波特无法或不愿担任，则我任命杰森·斯莫尔斯担任
as the executor of this will.
本遗嘱的执行人。
I herewith affix my signature to this will on this the 23rd of May, 2010 in the presence
我特此于2010年5月23日，在以下见证人面前签署本遗嘱，
of the following witnesses who witnessed and subscribed this will at my request and in
这些见证人应我的请求并在我面前见证并签署了本遗嘱。
my presence.
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at five key words on Language Takeaway.
现在，我们将在“语言小课堂”中学习五个关键词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小课堂。
Okay, the first word here in Language Takeaway comes from the very beginning of this monologue.
好的，“语言小课堂”中的第一个词来自这段独白的开头。
We're reading the last will in Testament aloud.
我们正在大声朗读这份最后的遗嘱和遗言。
I Luke Thompson residing in California being of sound mind.
我，卢克·汤普森，居住在加利福尼亚州，心智健全。
Sound as an adjective.
“Sound”作为形容词。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
That's very interesting.
这很有趣。
So he says, I am in sound mind and sound is an adjective to describe I am in a good state
所以他说，我心智健全，“sound”是一个形容词，用来描述我处于良好的
of mind.
精神状态。
That's right.
没错。
So he's not having any problems or logical or unaffected.
所以他没有任何问题，逻辑清晰或未受影响。
Basically I'm not crazy.
基本上就是我没疯。
Right.
对。
I'm not crazy.
我没疯。
I don't have any problems.
我没有任何问题。
We can say this about other things too.
我们也可以用它来形容其他事物。
We can say he's of sound body.
我们可以说他身体健康。
Right.
对。
That means that he is healthy.
那意味着他很健康。
He has no problems with his body.
他的身体没有任何问题。
Or I could say, Marco, that's a really good decision.
或者我可以说，Marco，那是个非常好的决定。
It's a sound decision.
那是个明智的决定。
So again, that's also a way of saying good or it will work.
所以，这也是表示好或可行的方式。
It will work.
可行。
It's a good decision.
那是个好决定。
Right.
对。
So you can use this adjective with sound body, sound mind or a sound decision.
所以你可以用这个形容词来形容“身体健康”、“心智健全”或“明智的决定”。
Or sometimes some people even say, I think in Ireland, they say, oh, he's a really sound
或者有时有些人甚至会说，我想在爱尔兰，他们会说，“哦，他真是个好人。”
guy.
Oh, so he's a good guy.
哦，所以他是个好人。
He's a good guy.
他是个好人。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
Yeah.
是的。
So sound body, sound mind, sound guy.
所以“身体健康”、“心智健全”、“好人”。
Moving on, he was talking about the will and he says, I hereby revoke all previous wills
继续，他谈到遗嘱时说：“我特此撤销所有先前的遗嘱
and codicils.
和遗嘱附录。”
The verb here is to revoke.
这里的动词是“撤销”。
To revoke.
“撤销”。
This is something that a lot of people hear in America when they drive their car too fast.
这是很多美国人在开车太快时会听到的词。
The police catch them and the police revoke their driver's license.
警察抓到他们，然后警察吊销他们的驾照。
And that basically means to take away.
这基本上意味着“拿走”或“撤销”。
That's right.
没错。
Or to take, right?
或者说“拿走”，对吧？
To take away from.
从……中拿走。
So this man here, Luke Thompson, what he's saying is, I revoke all previous wills.
所以这位卢克·汤普森先生说的是：我撤销所有之前的遗嘱。
That means any other will that I wrote before, it's not good anymore.
这意味着我之前写的任何其他遗嘱都不再有效了。
I'm throwing it away.
我要把它扔掉。
This is the only one that will exist.
这是唯一一份会存在的遗嘱。
So you can use this word revoke with many aspects.
所以“revoke”这个词可以用在很多方面。
For example, sometimes employees will get their benefits revoked by the company because
例如，有时员工会被公司撤销福利，因为
maybe they don't have enough money anymore.
可能公司资金不足了。
Or maybe they're bad employees.
或者他们是不好的员工。
Or maybe they were bad employees.
或者他们曾经是不好的员工。
That's too bad.
那太糟糕了。
All right.
好了。
So to revoke.
所以“revoke”就是撤销。
Now, moving on, he was talking about his estate.
现在，继续往下，他谈到了他的遗产。
So this is very interesting because he says, I give all the rest and residue of my estate
这很有趣，因为他说：我把所有剩余遗产
to my spouse.
留给我的配偶。
Okay, estate, it sounds like a very fancy word.
好的，“estate”听起来像是个很高级的词。
It is a fancy word.
它确实是个高级词。
Sometimes we use this word to mean someone's property, their house.
有时我们用这个词来指某人的财产，比如他们的房子。
But in a will, this means everything the person owns.
但在遗嘱中，这指的是这个人拥有的一切。
House, car, things, pets, stocks, investments.
房子、车、物品、宠物、股票、投资。
The estate is essentially everything the person owns as a kind of one unit.
“Estate”基本上就是把这个人拥有的一切视为一个整体。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So anything that is yours or you may have bought.
所以任何属于你的东西，或者你可能买过的东西。
Let's consider the estate is a big bag, right?
我们可以把遗产想象成一个大袋子，对吧？
That's your estate.
那就是你的遗产。
And inside this bag is everything that you own.
这个袋子里装着你拥有的一切。
You might see advertisements in fact in America or in England for estate sales.
事实上，在美国或英国，你可能会看到“遗产拍卖”的广告。
This means that when someone passes away, when they die, their family will sell their
这意味着当某人去世时，他们的家人会卖掉他们的
things and this is an estate sale.
物品，这就是遗产拍卖。
You can find beautiful, interesting things in estate sales.
你可以在遗产拍卖中找到漂亮、有趣的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
So that is a person's estate.
所以那就是一个人的遗产。
Now remember this is in the legal terms because you also have other things like real estate.
记住，这是法律术语，因为你还有别的东西，比如“房地产”。
And as you mentioned, which would be a house, right?
正如你提到的，那指的是房子，对吧？
Okay, now apart from his estate, he was telling everyone as to how they should take care of
好的，除了他的遗产，他还告诉大家该如何处理
his body or what they should do with it.
他的遗体，或者该怎么做。
And he said, well, I am to be cremated.
他说：我要被火化。
Okay, this is important.
好的，这很重要。
When a person dies, there are generally two options.
当一个人去世时，通常有两种选择。
Their body can be buried in a casket in the ground.
他们的遗体可以装在棺材里埋在地下。
That means they're put in the earth.
也就是说被放入土中。
But a lot of people choose to be cremated.
但很多人选择火化。
Okay, that means that their body will be burned and their ashes, that means the things that
好的，这意味着他们的遗体将被焚烧，而他们的骨灰，也就是焚烧后剩下的
are left after they are burned, they will be taken somewhere else.
东西，会被带到别处。
Like in a bowl or a pot.
比如放在碗或罐子里。
And in this case, that's what the person wants.
在这个例子中，这就是这个人想要的。
He wants to be cremated.
他想要被火化。
So that would be the verb to cremate and the noun would be a cremation.
所以动词是“cremate”，名词是“cremation”。
And what is going to happen to all this stuff?
所有这些财产会怎么处理呢？
Basically it's going to be given away to his wife, to English Pod, and to his heirs.
基本上，它们会被分给他的妻子、EnglishPod 和他的继承人。
This is our next word.
这是我们的下一个词。
What is an heir?
什么是“heir”？
Now, if you notice, the H is silent there.
注意，这里的 H 是不发音的。
So his heirs.
所以是“his heirs”。
And those are basically his children.
这些基本上就是他的孩子。
His daughters or his sons.
他的女儿或儿子。
Right, my heirs are the people who are related to me, who in this case will receive some
对，我的继承人就是与我有关的人，在这种情况下，他们会得到一些
of my things.
我的东西。
Now, is it only the children or also it could be maybe any other relative?
那么，只能是孩子吗？还是也可以是其他亲戚？
It could be any other relative.
可以是任何其他亲戚。
You could say, I'm his heir, he's my great uncle.
你可以说：我是他的继承人，他是我的叔祖父。
It means we're related but we're not necessarily father and daughter or grandfather and granddaughter.
这意味着我们有亲戚关系，但不一定是父女或祖孙关系。
An heir is someone who is related to the family.
“Heir”是指与家庭有血缘关系的人。
It doesn't have to be a certain relationship.
不一定是特定的关系。
And now it's interesting because from this word we can get inheritance.
有趣的是，从这个词我们可以得到“inheritance”。
Now we didn't find it in the dialogue.
我们在对话中没有找到这个词。
So it's very interesting because they're very similar in spelling, right?
所以很有趣，因为它们的拼写很相似，对吧？
Inheritance and heir.
“Inheritance”和“heir”。
Right, good to remember.
对，值得记住。
Yeah, good to remember.
是的，值得记住。
You switch the E and the I's, right?
你把 E 和 I 的位置调换了，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So inheritance is a thing.
所以“inheritance”是一件东西。
You can receive this.
你可以收到它。
So I received an inheritance from my great grandmother.
所以我从我曾祖母那里得到了一笔遗产。
That means I received some money or some things.
那意味着我收到了一些钱或一些东西。
That means you were that person's heir.
那意味着你是那个人的继承人。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Or in his inheritance, he received a large house.
或者在他的遗产中，他得到了一栋大房子。
He was the heir to a great fortune.
他是一笔巨大财富的继承人。
Okay, interesting.
好的，有意思。
So again, inheritance wasn't in the dialogue but I think it's worth mentioning.
所以再说一次，遗产这个词在对话中没有出现，但我认为值得提一下。
And I think now we can move on to four very interesting items that we have for you on
而且我认为现在我们可以继续讲四个非常有趣的条目，这些是我们为你们准备的
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升部分。
Okay, these first two are words that we normally read or hear in legal documents.
好的，前两个词是我们通常在法律文件中读到或听到的。
And I want to place emphasis on the fact that we don't really say them in spoken English.
我想强调一个事实，我们在口语中并不真的说这些词。
So remember that these are more formal terms.
所以记住这些是更正式的术语。
The first one is hereby.
第一个是“特此”。
I hereby declare.
我特此宣布。
That means now.
那意思是“现在”。
With this word, with this spoken sentence, this will happen.
通过这个词，通过这个说出的句子，这件事将会发生。
I think we've seen it like in movies sometimes.
我想我们有时在电影里见过它。
I hereby declare this country in the name of England.
我特此以英格兰的名义宣布这片土地。
I hereby declare you man and wife.
我特此宣布你们结为夫妻。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
That means in this moment, this happens.
那意思是此刻，这件事发生。
Okay.
好的。
And a very similar word that we also saw in the dialogue is herewith.
还有一个非常相似的词，我们在对话中也看到了，就是“随函”。
So in the Will and Testament, we hear Luke Thompson who says, I herewith affix my signature.
所以在遗嘱中，我们听到卢克·汤普森说：“我随函附上我的签名。”
That means with the action of signing my name, signing my signature, this will be completed.
那意思是随着签名的动作，签署我的名字，这件事将完成。
So I herewith, you have to have an action, not just a word.
所以“我随函”，你必须有一个动作，而不仅仅是一个词。
Okay.
好的。
So I herewith.
所以我随函。
I herewith attach my seal.
我随函附上我的印章。
A seal is like a stamp.
印章就像图章一样。
Very common in the old days when you had real letters.
在过去有实体信件的时候非常常见。
But I herewith attach my seal and give my approval to this document.
但我随函附上我的印章，并批准这份文件。
Okay.
好的。
So it has to be something physical.
所以它必须是某种物理的东西。
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
对。
So if maybe you're writing like this very classic letter and you say, I herewith include
所以如果你在写一封非常经典的信，你说：“我随函附上
a lock of my hair.
一缕我的头发。”
Oh, how romantic.
哦，真浪漫。
Okay.
好的。
That's kind of creepy.
那有点吓人。
But you're including or attaching physically, right?
但你是物理地附上或包含，对吧？
I guess the modern version of herewith would be attach.
我想“随函”的现代版本就是“附件”。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Good.
很好。
Herewith, hereby.
“随函”，“特此”。
We've got another phrase here that you might hear more commonly.
我们这里还有另一个短语，你可能更常听到。
The beginning of the Will and Testament, there's a phrase as follows.
遗嘱的开头有一个短语“如下”。
Okay.
好的。
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
我指示我的遗体处置如下。
So with my body do as follows.
所以对我的身体做如下处理。
So basically this is a very common way of putting this in a sentence to indicate that
所以基本上这是一种非常常见的在句子中表达的方式，用来表示
you're going to start to list items.
你要开始列举项目。
That's right.
没错。
Or give instructions.
或者给出指示。
Give instructions.
给出指示。
So for example, to make a loaf of bread, do as follows.
所以例如，要做一条面包，请按如下步骤操作。
Number one, get some flour.
第一，拿一些面粉。
Number two, add some water.
第二，加一些水。
So this is a way for us to say, listen, I'm going to give you instructions or a list.
所以这是一种方式，让我们说：“听着，我要给你指示或列表。
Pay attention.
注意听。”
So please do as follows.
所以请按如下步骤操作。
Please act as follows.
请按如下方式行动。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And our last word that we have here, going back to herewith, he said, I herewith affix
我们这里的最后一个词，回到“随函”，他说：“我随函
my signature.
附上我的签名。”
What does it mean when you affix?
“附上”是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
Affix is a word we have a number of other words for these days, so you rarely hear it.
“附上”这个词我们现在有很多其他词可以替代，所以你很少听到它。
It means to attach or to include.
它的意思是“附加”或“包含”。
Okay.
好的。
So I herewith affix my signature would be attach my signature.
所以“我随函附上我的签名”就是“附加我的签名”。
Right.
对。
I herewith provide my signature or I herewith affix my address or I herewith affix something.
我随函提供我的签名，或者我随函附上我的地址，或者我随函附上某物。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Really interesting stuff.
真是有趣的内容。
You'll obviously see this very commonly with legal documents such as these, even though
你显然会经常在像这样的法律文件中看到这种用法，尽管
it is like older English, it's still very commonly used.
它有点像古英语，但仍然非常常用。
I guess because the law is so old.
我猜是因为法律本身很古老。
That's right.
没错。
Definitely.
确实如此。
And I think that it's worth listening to today's monologue one more time.
而且我认为值得再听一遍今天的独白。
Think about some of the words that we've just discussed and we'll be back in a moment.
想想我们刚刚讨论过的一些单词，我们一会儿就回来。
Last will and testament of Luke Thompson.
卢克·汤普森的最终遗嘱。
I Luke Thompson residing in California, being of sound mind do hereby declare this instrument
我，卢克·汤普森，居住在加利福尼亚州，心智健全，特此声明这份文件
to be my last will and testament.
是我的最终遗嘱。
I hereby revoke all previous wills and codicils.
我特此撤销所有先前的遗嘱和遗嘱附录。
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
我指示我的遗体处理方式如下。
I'm to be cremated and taken to the summit of Mount Everest where my ashes will forever
我将被火化，并带到珠穆朗玛峰之巅，我的骨灰将永远
remain at the ceiling of the earth.
留在地球的最高点。
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to my spouse, Betty Thompson, should she survive
我将我遗产的所有剩余部分给予我的配偶贝蒂·汤普森，如果她在我去世后
me for 60 days.
存活60天。
If my spouse, Betty Thompson, does not survive me, I give all the rest and residue of my
如果我的配偶贝蒂·汤普森未能在我之后存活，我将我遗产的所有剩余部分给予
estate to English Pod.
English Pod。
If neither Betty Thompson nor English Pod survives me, I give all the rest and residue
如果贝蒂·汤普森和English Pod都未能在我之后存活，我将所有剩余部分
of my estate to my heirs as determined by the laws of the state of California relating
我的遗产将根据加利福尼亚州关于继承和分配的法律，由我的法定继承人继承。
to descent and distribution.
关于继承和分配的法律。
I appoint Robert Porter to act as the executor of this will, to serve without bond.
我指定罗伯特·波特担任本遗嘱的执行人，无需提供担保。
Should Robert Porter be unable or unwilling to serve, then I appoint Jason Smalls to act
如果罗伯特·波特无法或不愿担任，则我指定杰森·斯莫尔斯担任
as the executor of this will.
本遗嘱的执行人。
I herewith affix my signature to this will on this the 23rd of May, 2010 in the presence
我特此于2010年5月23日，在以下见证人的见证下签署本遗嘱，
of the following witnesses who witnessed and subscribed this will at my request and in
这些见证人应我的请求并在我面前见证并签署了本遗嘱。
my presence.
在我面前。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So this is a very interesting topic.
所以这是一个非常有趣的话题。
Now I wonder, within the will or within the estate, do you also acquire a person's debts?
我想知道，在遗嘱或遗产中，你是否也会继承一个人的债务？
Ah, that's a good question.
啊，这是个好问题。
Because I know in some countries you do, in some countries you don't.
因为我知道在一些国家你会继承，在一些国家你不会。
I know in like some cases, some heirs have found themselves in some legal problems because
我知道在某些情况下，一些继承人发现自己陷入了一些法律问题，因为
all of a sudden they inherited that person's debts and stuff like that.
突然之间他们继承了那个人的债务之类的东西。
I think that does happen, especially for people whose properties are mortgaged.
我认为这种情况确实会发生，尤其是对于那些财产被抵押的人。
For example, if your uncle has a house and he didn't pay for it with cash, he has a mortgage
例如，如果你的叔叔有一栋房子，他不是用现金买的，而是有抵押贷款，
and he dies and you inherit this house, you also inherit the mortgage.
他去世了，你继承了这栋房子，你也同时继承了抵押贷款。
So sometimes inheritances are not always a good thing.
所以有时候继承并不总是一件好事。
I think this happened more in the past.
我认为这在过去更常见。
There are more protections and safeguards for people today.
如今人们有更多的保护措施和保障。
But definitely, I mean, what is it like in Ecuador?
但说真的，厄瓜多尔的情况是怎样的？
Do people inherit debt?
人们会继承债务吗？
Yeah, I think most, well, obviously most banks when they give out loans or a mortgage, they
是的，我想大多数——嗯，显然大多数银行在发放贷款或抵押贷款时，会
have somebody that will kind of co-sign on these things.
找一个人来共同签署这些文件。
And I imagine, I'm not really very sure, but I know that if you inherit an estate that
我想，虽然我不太确定，但我知道如果你继承了一处
has a mortgage, you are forced to pay it.
有抵押贷款的房产，你就必须偿还它。
And if you can't, then they will make that other person who co-signed it responsible
如果你还不起，那么他们就会让那个共同签署的人负责，
if he still exists.
如果他还活着的话。
I don't know.
我不知道。
In these legal systems, it's sometimes very strange because it seems like there would
在这些法律体系中，有时很奇怪，因为似乎会有
be a lot of gaps.
很多漏洞。
That's right.
没错。
And everyone wants to protect themselves.
每个人都想保护自己。
So we've got the bank that wants to protect itself.
所以银行想保护自己。
It gives a loan, it wants the money back.
它发放贷款，就想要回钱。
And a person who wants to protect himself from maybe a relative who dies and has debt.
而一个人想保护自己，以免亲戚去世后留下债务。
So I'm curious to know what our users have to say.
所以我很好奇我们的用户会怎么说。
What is the situation in your country?
你们国家的情况是怎样的？
Do most people have a will and testament?
大多数人都有遗嘱吗？
What happens with debt?
债务会怎么样？
Or what happens if somebody dies and they don't have a will and testament?
或者如果某人去世了却没有遗嘱，会发生什么？
That's a good question too.
这也是个好问题。
I don't have an answer for that one.
那个问题我没有答案。
Alright, so let us know and we'll give you guys some information on that as well.
好吧，告诉我们，我们也会给你们一些相关信息。
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。